<resources>
    <string name="app_name">GEM</string>

    <string name="k1">Akhenaten: Before the fifth year of his reign, he was also known as Amenhotep IV. Pharaoh of the Eighteenth Dynasty ruled Egypt for 17 years. He is best known for renouncing the plurality of traditional Egyptian deities and introducing a new cult centered on Aton, which is sometimes described as a monotheistic or hinotistic.</string>
    <string name="k2">Amenhotep 3: In the early years of his reign, Amenhotep the Third was interested in sports, especially hunting and hunting, where he was a great hunter, where he found a scarab in which he recorded that he had captured 100 wild bulls in a two -day royal hunting trip and another scarab issued in the tenth year in which he stated that since his ascension the throne had killed 102 lions On fishing trips. He showed little interest in the war, as Amenhotep III faced some unrest in his fifth year in Nush, but fighting was taking place with a small group of rebels. After he defeated them, he expanded his monarchy until he reached the fourth waterfall. He wrote a memorial for the expedition near the rocks of the island of Nunusu in Nubia. Another revolt took place in the town of Abhat after the second waterfall, and the Nuba had a self-administration under the royal son of Kush.</string>
    <string name="k3">Hatshepsut: (meaning: of the most noble ladies of 1508 -1458 BC) was the fifth pharaoh of the Eighteenth Dynasty in ancient Egypt. Egyptologists consider her one of the most successful pharaohs, holding him the longest title of any other woman in Egyptian captivity. Her reign was marked by the strength of the army, the construction, and her journeys. She is the eldest daughter of Pharaoh of Egypt King Thutmose I and her mother Queen Ahmos. Her father, the king, had given birth to an illegitimate son, Tuthmosis the Second. He accepted the marriage of him to the custom of royal families to join together in ruling after his death, as a solution to the problem of having a legitimate .heir This queen left many mysteries and secrets, perhaps the most exciting mystery of the character Snmot, the architect who built her famous temple in DeirelBahari.</string>
    <string name="k4">Nefertiti: was an Egyptian queen and the Great Royal Wife of Akhenaten, an Egyptian Pharaoh. Nefertiti and her husband were known for a religious revolution, in which they worshipped one god only, Aten, or the sun disc. With her husband, she reigned at what was arguably the wealthiest period of Ancient Egyptian history. Some scholars believe that Nefertiti ruled briefly as Neferneferua ten after her husband\'s death and before the accession of Tutankhamun, although this identification is a matter of ongoing debate. If Nefertiti did rule as Pharaoh, her reign was marked by the fall of Amarna and relocation of the capital back to the traditional city of.</string>
    <string name="k5">Tutankhamun, one of the pharaohs of the eighteenth Egyptian family in the history of ancient Egypt, was the Pharaoh of Egypt from 1334 to 1325 BC. In the era of the modern state. Tutankhamun is one of the most famous of the Pharaohs for reasons not related to the achievements he has achieved or wars he won, as is the case with many Pharaohs; but for other reasons that are historically important, most notably the discovery of his tomb and his treasures completely without any damage. The mystery surrounding the circumstance s of his death as many considered the death of Pharaoh at a very young age is abnormal, especially with the effects of fractures in the bones of the thigh and skull, and the marriage of his minister to his widow after his death and the inauguration of Pharaoh himself. All these mysterious events, and the heavy use of the myth of the Pharaohs curse associated with the tomb of Tutankhamun used in movies and video games made Tutankhamun the most famous puzzles for puzzles and still unanswered questions, considered by some of the earliest assassination s in the history of humanity. He was buried in his tomb - Cemetery 62 - in the Valley .of the Kings Tutankhamun was nine when Pharaoh of Egypt and his name in ancient Egyptian meant "the living image of the god Amun", the great ancient Egyptian goddess. Tutankhamun lived in a transitional period in the history of ancient Egypt, where he came after Akhenaten, who tried to unite the gods of ancient Egypt in the form of a single god Sunday.</string>

    <string name="m1">Anubis: God of death, mummification on, embalming, the afterlife, cemeteries, tombs, the Underworld. Anubis or Anpu in Ancient Egyptian, is the Greek name of the god of death, mummification on, embalming, the afterlife, cemeteries, tombs, and the Underworld, in ancient Egyptian religion, usually depicted as a canine or a man with a canine head. Archeologists have identified Anubis\'s sacred animal as an Egyptian canid, the African golden wolf. Like many ancient Egyptian deities, Anubis assumed different roles in various contexts. Depicted as a protector of graves as early as the First Dynasty, Anubis was also an embalmer. By the Middle Kingdom, he was replaced by Osiris in his role as lord of the underworld. One of his prominent roles was as a god who ushered souls into the afterlife. He attended the weighing scale during the "Weighing of the Heart," in which it was determined whether a soul would be allowed to enter the realm of the dead. Despite being one of the most ancient and "one of the most frequently depicted and mentioned gods" in the Egyptian pantheon, Anubis played almost no role in Egyptian myths. Anubis was depicted in black, a color that symbolized regeneration, life, the soil of the Nile River, and the discoloration of the corpse after embalming. Anubis is associated with his brother Wepwawet, another Egyptian god portrayed with a dog\'s head or in canine form, but with grey or white fur. Historians assume that the two figures were eventually combined.</string>
    <string name="m2">Jackal: The Anubis Shrine was found behind the unwilled entrance which leads from the grave chamber into the so-called "Store Room" (JA). The shrine, with a figure of Anubis on top, was facing towards the west. Behind it was the Canonic chest with the Pharaoh\'s canonic jars inside. During the work in the grave chamber, the entrance to the Store Room was blocked with wooden boards, so that the clearance work in the grave chamber would not damage the objects in the Store Room. Investigating and clearing the Store Room began in the fifth excavation season (22 September 1926 – 3 May 1927) and Carter first described the Anubis Shrine in his excavation journal on 23 October 1927.The statue of the Anubis, depicted completely in animal form as a recumbent jackal, was attached to the roof of the shrine. The statue is made from wood, covered with black paint. The insides of the ears, the eyebrows, and the rims of the eyes, and the collar and the band knotted around the neck, are worked in gold leaf. The whites of the eyes are made from calcite and the pupils from obsidian. The claws are in silver, which was more valuable than gold in Ancient Egypt.</string>
    <string name="m3">Osiris: Osiris, the god of the Baath and the arithmetic, is the head of the Court of the Dead of the Ancient Egyptians, one of the gods of the ninth sacred master of the ancient Egyptian religion. According to ancient Egyptian religious myth Osiris was the brother of Isis and Nephthys West, and he married Isis. According to the Egyptian legend, his evil brother Set was murdered by the evil symbol, where he performed a festive ceremony in which he displayed a wonderful ark, the audience slept in it, but it was only suitable for Osiris and then threw Set in the River Nile and severed and threw it. To various parts of the Nile Valley, Isis and her sister cried a lot and began her journey in search of her husband\'s body parts. Everywhere she found a part of his body, the Egyptians built temples such as the Temple of Abydos dating to this incident and the site of the temple was built in the first capital of ancient Egypt (Abydos), where the head of Osiris is found in the drawings of the temple erected by King S. The famous frescoes illustrate what Isis had assembled for Osiris\'s body and then the process of intercourse between them to bear their son Horus, who was fighting to take his father\'s revenge from his uncle and because of his victory over death, Osiris gave eternal and divine life to the Second World. They are "Habi", "Amsti", "Dumotif" ("protector of his mother") and "Khabshanov" (meaning "drink to his brother"). In the Book of the Dead there is usually a picture of Osiris sitting on a throne in the Hereafter and behind him his sister Isis and Nephthys. In front of him, his four young sons, Horus, assist him in calculating the dead .The ancient Egyptian conceived that Horus would come to the dead after successfully passing the scale and present it to Osiris.</string>
    <string name="m4">Sekhmet: of the gods in ancient Egyptian mythology. Often represented as a lady with a lioness head sitting on the throne or standing. Is one of the members of the Triad of Memphis (Petah - Sekhmet - Nefertam) Female goddess. Her titles: The Great Lady of Mahaboobah Ptah, Ein Ra, Our Lady of War, Our Lady of the Earths (Upper and Lower Egypt), Our Lady of the Land of Libya, the mighty and many other titles. The lioness is the sacred animal of the goddess of Memphis Sekhmet, whose strong name means .Sekhmet, meaning the strong, was always represented as a lady with a lioness head or as a lady and a lioness head sitting on the throne adorned with the sign of the unification of north and south Egypt and holding her hand the key to life Ankh, topped by the sun disk and cobra snake. The center of worship was in Memphis and was considered the wife of Ptah and the mother of Nefertum, the god of the lotus, where they represented the triad of Memphis (Ptah Sekhmet and their son Nefertum) Ra the sun god Ra in the ancient Egyptian belief angered humans to mock them. He sent Sekhmet to avenge them. The avenged image of Hathor. In order to kill these people. Sekhmet, however, enjoyed this task so much so that people wiped out almost all human beings. Here Ra deceived Sekhmet by giving her large quantities of red colored beer, which resembles the color of blood, so she drank it and drunk and calmed until she stopped killing.</string>
    <string name="m5">Sphynx cat: Cats were known in ancient Egypt as "Mao", and they had an important place in ancient Egyptian society. Based on recent DNA comparisons of living species, it is estimated that cats first domesticated about 2000 years ago in the Fertile Crescent region. After thousands of years, the religion of ancient Egyptians became related to animals, including cats.</string>

    <string name="s1">Ancient Egyptian golden ark: The Ark of the Covenant also known as the Ark of the Testimony, and in a few verses across various translations as the Ark of Gods a gold-covered wooden chest with lid cover described in the Book of Exodus as containing the two stone tablets of the Ten Commandments. According to various texts within the Hebrew Bible, it also contained Aaron\'s rod and a pot of manna. Hebrews describes: "The ark of the covenant was covered on all sides with gold, in which was a golden jar holding the manna, and Aaron\'s rod which budded, and the tablets of the covenant ".The biblical account relates that, approximately one year after the Israelites\' exodus from Egypt, the Ark was created according to the pattern given to Moses by God when the Israelites were encamped at the foot of biblical Mount Sinai.</string>
    <string name="s2">Ankh: Ankh is an ancient Egyptian hieroglyphic symbol that was most commonly used in writing and in Egyptian art to represent the word for "life" and, by extension, as a symbol of life itself. The ankh has a cross shape but with an oval loop in place of an upper bar. The origins of the symbol are not known, although many hypotheses have been proposed. It was used in writing as a trilateral sign. This sequence was found in several Egyptian words, including the words meaning "mirror", "floral bouquet", and "life". In art the symbol often appeared as a physical object representing either life or substances such as air or water that are related to it. It was especially commonly held in the hands of ancient Egyptian deities, or being given by them to the pharaoh, to represent their power to sustain life and to revive human souls in the afterlife. The ankh was one of the most common decorative motifs in ancient Egypt and was also used decoratively by neighboring cultures. Coptic Christians adapted it into a shape with a circular rather than oval loop, and used it as a variant of the Christian cross. Since the late 20th century, in the Western world, the ankh has again come to be used decoratively, as a symbol of African cultural identity.</string>
    <string name="s3">Ivory bracelet: The bracelets, worn in the wrist, were the most beautiful bracelets that were found in the tombs of princesses of the Twelfth Dynasty, and women still adorn them so far .One of the earliest bracelets found in Egypt in ancient times is bracelets found in the tomb of Jar in Abydos from the Early Dynasty.</string>
    <string name="s4">The Usekh or Wesekh is a personal ornament, a type of broad collar or necklace, familiar to many because of its presence in images of the ancient Egyptian elite. Deities, women, and men were depicted wearing this jewelry. One example can be seen on the famous gold mask of Tutankhamun. The ancient word wsẖ can mean "breadth" or "width" in the Ancient Egyptian language and so this adornment is often referred to as the broad collar .The usekh broad collar was wrapped around and supported by the neck and shoulders. It is typically adorned with closely placed rows of colored stone beads, or it is made entirely of metal. The collars were connected with clasps of gold.</string>
    <string name="s5">One of the most intricately decorated objects in the tomb, this wooden chest, which was found in the Antechamber, illustrates the innovation of the frenzied battle. A fierce confrontation takes place on both sides of the box; pictured here is the king in his chariot fighting against the Asiatic. On the other side the king battles against the Nubians. Scenes such as these were the apparent influence for the artists who composed the military reliefs for the pharaohs of the Nineteenth Dynasty, where the enemy is also frequently depicted as a confused mass without the traditional registers. The absence of these ground lines make possible the chaotic disarray of the enemy. Chaos and disorder were anathema to the ancient Egyptian, since they represented the opposites of maat, the balance and harmony upon which the entire culture was based. These battle scenes, therefore, appear to have symbolic significance .The curved lid is divided into two sections, each of which has a horizontal panel portraying the king pursuing wild animals. The smaller sides each have two representations of Tutankhamun as a sphinx treading upon his enemies. On the long horizontal panel here, the king shoots his arrows into the fray. Behind him are three registers of subordinate personnel. The inscription before Tutankhamun refers to him as: "The good god, the Son of Amon, the Valiant one, without his equal, A Possessor of strength who tramples hundreds of thousands, who makes them into a pile of corpses." Both his throne name, Nebkheperur a, and his personal name, Tutankhamun, appearing under the designation, the "good god, Son of Ra", are written in front of him.</string>

    <string name="w1">Egypt weapon: Axe Weapon Cutting weapons are intended to cause large, medium-depth wounds to the opponent, and the location of these wounds is unimportant. For example, a weapon bearer may target the thigh or hummers and not necessarily a killer position. It causes severe bleeding due to the widening of the wound and the opponent loses consciousness in minutes and often loses his life in no more than an hour. Therefore, the cutting weapons have gained great popularity as the warrior can eliminate his opponent by any successful strike anywhere in the body unlike the stabbing weapons. Do not kill if you hit a leg or arm, in turn most cutting weapons suffer from ineffective gears and armor. The categorical ax is the main weapon of Egyptian forces in close combat Industry: A war ax cutter from a long wooden handle that ends with a half-circle copper blade on one side of the handle The pattern of use, almost all soldiers carry the war axes as a secondary weapon after the bayonet, and used after the overlap of the ranks of the soldiers and enemies in individual combat, but the groups of soldiers tasked to protect the archers were the cutter ax is their main weapon in addition to a large gear and wood gear Covering the body from the top of the head to the feet and used by the guard as a wall to protect the archers from throwing enemies or attacks with spears, these guards did not dream of bayonets because the arrival of the enemies to them means to engage in close combat.</string>
    <string name="w2">Khopesh sword: The Khopesh sword was cast entirely of bronze and the handle then wound with hide and cloth and, with more expensive blades, ornamented. This curved sword was much more effective than any the Egyptians had used in the past. The war chariot, manned by archers with the new composite bow and a large quiver attached to the side, would prove one of Egypt\'s most significant military assets, and the battle axe, made of bronze attached to a haft, was far more effective than the flint or copper axes bound to wooden shafts in the past. The slicing axe is probably the only weapon which Hyksos technology could not improve upon. The Hyksos did far more than simply provide the Egyptians with better weapons; they gave them a reason to use them. Egypt had never been governed by a foreign power before, but during the Second Intermediate Period, the Hyksos held the ports of Lower Egypt and a significant amount of territory in the region while the Nubians had been able to expand into Upper Egypt and establish fortifications there. Only Thebes in Upper Egypt, between these two foreign powers, was ruled by Egyptians until Ahmose I of Thebes (c. 1570–1544 BCE) drove the Hyksos from the country, defeated the Nubians, and unified Egypt under his rule, initiating the New Kingdom. Interestingly, excavations at the site of Avaris have uncovered weapons of both the Hyksos and the Egyptian forces from the assault of Ahmose I. These finds show that the Hyksos\' blades had become inferior not only to the Egyptians\' but to their own earlier work. It seems that, by this time, the Hyksos were making weapons largely for ceremonial, rather than practical use.</string>
    <string name="w3">Repressed weapon: The oppression is the weapon of the kings of the Pharaohs. The ax is one of two weapons developed from the old stone ax, and that ax was made of a wooden handle and installed from the top sharp stone formation from one side or two, has been divided from the old stone ax two weapons are the oppressor and war axes of all kinds, but the repression is a direct extension of the stone ax Industry: The funnel is made of a long wooden handle that ends with a spherical stone head of elliptical stone (bone) or bones or copper, and some of the luxurious collections that were made for the kings of Egypt end with a stone or metal piece in the form of a thick, sharp disc. Paranoiac inscriptions .Pattern of use: The funnel is a rather brutal weapon, and the funnel targets the bones and its preferred target is the head, and the blow of the funnel is able to crush the skull easily unless the opponent wears the helmet, and the second favorite targets of the funnel is the ribs and the bones of the chest where the head of the funnel hits the fractures Fatal because of broken limbs entering the lungs causing respiratory problems ending with painful death, the secondary objectives of the repressive are the bones of the hands and legs where they can cause fractures or cracks, and the repressive did not retain its long position as a weapon of close combat between the Egyptian forces where Unequivocal war of displacement from their place.</string>
    <string name="w4">Scythe of Anubis: One of Anubis\'s roles was the "balancer." The scene depicting the weight of the heart shows, in the Book of the Dead, Anubis performs a measurement that determines whether a person is worth entering the world of the dead (underworld, known as Dawat). By assessing the heart of the deceased person through Maat (or "truth"), which was often represented as an ostrich feather, Anubis determined the fate of souls. Nation will devour heavier spirits than feather, while lighter spirits of feather rise into heavenly existence. In funerary contexts, Anubis appears while preparing the mummy of a deceased person or sitting on a grave protecting him. The seals of the New Kingdom tombs depict Anubis sitting above the nine arches representing his dominance over Egypt\'s enemies.</string>
    <string name="w5">Tutankhamun Iron Dagger: discovered in 1925 in Tutankhamun\'s 14th Century BC King\'s Valley tomb by archaeologist Howard Carter, the iron dagger is of meteorite origin Nineteen objects were discovered in the tomb of Tutankhamun, including a set of blades which appear very similar to those used in the Egyptian opening of the mouth ceremony (a ritual performed for the benefit of the deceased to enable an afterlife). These blades are also intricately linked to iron and stars, being described in temple inventories as composed of iron and were themselves frequently referred to as the stars. The other iron objects were wrapped with Tutankhamun\'s mummy; these include a miniature headrest contained inside the golden death mask, an amulet attached to a golden bracelet and a dagger blade with gold haft. All were made by relatively crude methods with the exception of the dagger blade which is clearly expertly produced. This suggests that the dagger was probably imported to Egypt perhaps as a royal gift from a neighboring territory, indicating that at this time Egypt\'s knowledge and skills of iron production were relatively limited. Only further analytical testing can confirm if all of these artifacts are made from meteorite iron but they do appear to suggest that iron was a material used to indicate high status at the time of Tutankhamun\'s death in approximately 1327 BC.</string>
</resources>